幻灯片放在哪儿
Where are those projections?
3  6  9号都在各自文件夹里
Three, six and nine are in their folders.
我想再...  很好
Can I have some more... Excellent.
茶在桌上了  你好
Tea's at your seat. Hello.
稍等
Oh, hold on.
又是本·费德曼
Ben Federman again,
要再做一次会前通气
another pre-call.
已经通过气了  这算是"后"通气电话吗
We did the pre-call. Is this the post pre-call call?
董事会想了解进军亚洲市场的细节
The board's gonna want specifics with the push into the Asian markets.
本  哪里有什么进军亚洲的细节
Ben, there are no specifics about Asia.
我们可是在凌晨3点才想出国际化计划的方案
We came up with that as a Hail Mary at 3:00 in the morning...
Hail Mary  万福玛丽传球
[成功率低的孤注一掷的长距离传球]
去应付董事会
to placate the board about international.
卡莉  我只是给你提个醒
Carly, I'm just giving you a heads-up about Asia.
没有进军亚洲市场的细节
There is no Asia.
让我们谈谈亚洲市场
Let's talk about Asia.
我们正在与里昂信贷接触
We're in the preliminary stages
欲与其结成战略伙伴
of forming a strategic alliance with Credit Lyonnais.
3个月后  走上韩国街道
Within three months, you won't
广告牌或药妆店的橱窗里
be able to walk four feet in Kangham, South Korea
我们的靓丽模特
without seeing one of our beautiful models
会让您目不暇接
smiling at you from billboards
向你微笑  邀请你进店
and drugstore windows, inviting you in.
卡莉  真是天大的好消息
That's incredible news, Carly.
我们期待了解些亚洲市场的情况
We'd hoped to hear something about Asia.
但没想到已经进行到这一步了
Had no idea plans were so far along.
要知道亚洲嘛  总是犹抱琵琶半遮面
Well, you know Asia. Nothing's done until it's done.
卡莉  我很好奇
Carly, I was wondering,
能谈谈
could you walk us through what
对亚洲其他地区的想法吗
you were thinking for other Asian territories?
当然  印度的女性人口超过5亿
Absolutely. India has over half a billion women.
她们的购买力使这个国家
In terms of spending power,
成为世界上最有潜力的单体市场
it's the single largest potential market in the world.
我们收购了一家当地公司以
Um, we have retained a local firm
减少文化差异
to ensure that cultural differences are respected.
不过  我今天无法
Um, however, I can't go into
向各位展示更多细节了
the specifics of my plan with you until tomorrow.
现在又有一个会要用这间会议室
Right now I have a meeting and I need the room.
我们的会议可才刚开始
We were just getting started.
我知道  我真心致歉
I know and I do apologize.
是临时决定的
It's last minute,
有3位国务院官员前来协商
but the meeting is with three state
打通进军中国市场的渠道
department officials to smooth the way for China.
中国市场吗  真是太好了
China? This is just incredible.
-再联络  -谢谢你
- We'll be in touch. - Thank you.
-怎么了  -我需要看医生
- What is it? - I need a doctor.
我的腿动不了了
I can't move my leg.
32岁女性
32-year-old female,
右腿麻痹  伴有疼痛  说吧
paralysis and severe pain in her right quad. Go.
她怎么找到你的
How'd she get to you?
她是索妮欧化妆品公司的首席执行官
She's the C.E.O. of Sonyo Cosmetics.
3位助理和15位副总裁
Three assistants and 15 v.P.'s checked out
研究决定她的医生人选
who should be treating her.
最终选了谁  我  殊途同归啊
Who da man? I da man. I always suspected.
豪斯医生  虽然可能性渺茫
Dr. House, I know the chances are very slim,
但我想你也意识到
but I'm sure you recognize...
她可能和你一样  腿部有血栓
that she may have what you had, a clot in her thigh.
太扯了
A bit of a long shot.
会不会是椎间盘突出
What about a disk herniation?
不会吧  艾瑞克
I don't know, Eric.
如果她是椎间盘突出
If her disk were herniated,
她会全身疼痛  不是吗
she'd present with pain elsewhere, wouldn't she?
-是的  我想是  -没错
- Yeah, I suppose. - You're right.
最有可能是血栓  对吗  罗伯特
A clot's also the most deadly, right, Robert?
对  一旦血栓破裂  她会中风并死亡
True. The clot breaks off, she could stroke and die.
豪斯医生  我认为他们的判断是正确的
Dr. House, I believe that they're right-
-别说了  -怎么了
- Stop talking. - What?
嚼了本谈判手册  是不是
You read one of those negotiating books, didn't you?
《谈判力》  《赢得谈判50法》
Getting to Yes. Fifty Ways to Win an Argument.
《合伙人漫游指南》
Hitchhiker's Guide to Being a Pal.
5秒钟内
In five seconds,
你控制他们认同了你的观点
you just manipulated these two into agreeing with your point of view.
伙计们  这是弱势方谈判策略
Fellas, this is known as soft positional bargaining.
没用的
It's not gonna work.
豪斯医生  那你的意思是她有
Dr. House, are you saying that she doesn't have a clot,
还是没有血栓呢
or are you saying that if she does have a clot,
不需要给她用血液稀释剂  做血管造影吗
she doesn't need blood thinners and an angiogram?
奇斯  给她用血液稀释剂
Chase, put her on blood thinners.
做个血管造影
Do an angiogram.
如果结果呈阴性  做脊椎核磁共振成像
When that comes back negative, M.R.I. The spine.
如果是阳性  开刀做腿部组织活检
If that's clean, cut her open and biopsy the leg.
这才对
Excellent suggestion.
少读书  多看电视
Read less, more TV.
很少有个人捐赠
It's rare for an individual to make a donation...
可以对医院这样庞大复杂的机构
significant enough to impact an
有如此之影响
organization as large and unwieldy as a hospital.
同时  这笔捐赠有一个附加条件
This donation does come with one string,
捐赠者将成为董事长
that he be made chairman of the board.
我认为这是一个合理要求
I think that's a reasonable request.
他有权获知
I think he should have the right to know
我们如何使用他的1亿美元
what it is we do with his $ 100 million.
欢迎我们的新董事长
Please welcome our new chairman of the board,
爱德华·沃格勒
Edward Vogler.
谢谢
Thank you.
我18岁那年
When I was 18,
我父亲借给我两万块作大学学费
my dad loaned me $20,000 for a college tuition,
后来他才知道那是个错误
which he would have known was a mistake
因为我并没有上大学
had he known I wasn't actually in college.
我拿了他的钱
I took his money
投资于一个做小生意的朋友身上
and invested in a friend who had a little business.
当我父亲发现那笔钱的真实用处后
And when my dad found out what I had done with his money,
他就不怎么和我交流了
he and I didn't talk much after that.
但我朋友的生意做成了
But my friend's business took off,
我用获得的利润
and I used the profits from that
收购一家又一家公司
to buy another company and another.
我一定是很擅长做这个  眼光不错
And I must have been pretty good at it, had a good eye,
因为在我发觉之前
because before I knew it,
人们已经开始对我的公司报价了
people were making offers for my company.
大约1年前  我的公司上市
And about a year ago, I went public,
于是一夜之间  我身价十亿
and overnight I was worth a billion dollars.
所以  我回去看我父亲
So, I went to see my dad.
我承认  我想看到点儿什么
I'll admit. I wanted a little payback.
我想看他听到我成功了的表情
You know, kind of shove the win in his face.
于是  我回去了
So, I drove upstate,
坐在伴我长大的那个厨房里
and sat in the kitchen I grew up in,
他却没有反应
and, uh, he had no reaction.
不是他想那样  他甚至认不出我是谁
It wasn't his fault. He didn't even know who I was,
因为他的老年痴呆症恶化了
because his Alzheimer's had taken a turn for the worse,
用上最好的药和医护条件也无能为力
despite the best drugs and care out there.
这也是我站在这里的原因
And that is why I'm here.
要是我对这家医院的捐赠
What if my contribution to this hospital
带来了癌症从无法治愈到有法可循的转变呢
is the difference between no cure and a cure for cancer?
或是让
The difference between
一个35年来都认不出他妻子的男人
a man not recognizing his wife of 35 years
可以看着她妻子轻语
and being able to look at her and say,
"早安  亲爱的  我爱你"
"Good morning, honey. I love you."
只要有一种疾病还在伤害人类生命
If there's a disease out there killing people,
我就会给你一张空白支票去与之抗争
I am writing you a blank check to fight back.
一切  都会大为不同
So, things are going to change a lot.
你最好关掉手机
We're gonna have to ask you for the cell phone.
干你自己的活  少来烦我
Do what you need to do. I'm okay.
我可以肯定地告诉你
I'm pretty sure
X光机会毁掉你的手机
my X-ray machine can take your phone in a fight.
就像油煎一样
It'll fry it.
好吧
Fine.
-她年龄多大  -32
- How old is she? - Thirty-two.
她这么年轻就当上了上市公司的首席执行官
Wow. And she's already the C.E.O. of a public company.
她是个工作狂  好了  卡莉  别动
She's a workaholic. Okay, Carly, hold still.
X光将会射过你的腿部
The X-ray machine is gonna pass over your leg.
好的
Okay.
休假息时你都做些什么
What'd you do with your time off?
去格施塔德滑雪
Snowboarding in Gstaad.
是瑞士吧
Switzerland.
你玩双板还是单板  你可以和我一起去
Do you ski or board? You can come with if you like.
在周游世界之前
Maybe we should start with a drink
我们是不是该一起喝一杯
before we go around the world.
你想和我喝一杯啊
Oh, you wanna have a drink with me?
很主动的  我喜欢
Oh, very aggressive. I like that.
我想用做生意的方法管理这里
I wanna run this place like a business.
怎么   在走廊里多放几个自动贩售机吗
What, you want to put more vending machines in the hallway?
或者赌博轮盘
Maybe a roulette wheel?
不错的主意  但我是认真的
Nice one. But I'm serious.
你出售的产品是健康
The product that you're selling is good health.
这应该不难卖
It shouldn't be a tough sell.
要是你不想出售
If you don't wanna sell,
就意味着你不在乎人们能否得到你的产品
it means you don't care if people get your product.
你在乎消费者的健康吗
You care if people are healthy,
还是说你对自己的产品相当自信
or are you too proud for that?
那个人是谁
Who's that?
是我们的众多医生中的一员
Oh, that's just one of our doctors.
医生不是都要穿白大褂的吗
Aren't, uh, doctors supposed to wear lab coats?
-他有点儿特别  -最受欢迎的人
- He's different. - Everyone's buddy.
-不  不完全是  -那为什么他不穿
- No, not exactly. - Then why does he get away with it?
只是一件外套而已  他是相当优秀的人才
It's just a coat. He's very good.
-说"啊 "  -啊
- Say '"Ah." - Ah.
再大声一点  就像要呕吐一样
Now really belt it out, like you're gonna throw up.
非常好
Perfect.
好了  这样就行了
Okay, that's it.
几天内我们就会知道
We should know in a couple of days
你儿子嗓子里长的是什么了
what's growing in your son's throat.
在听吗
Hello?
-他不能说话  -什么
- He can't talk. - Excuse me?
-他做过个膝盖手术  -然后呢
- He had knee surgery. - Right?
大概一年前他做了手术  然后就不能说话了
About a year ago, and then he couldn't talk.
对  没错  手术后他就不能说话
Right. Yeah, well, that happens.
要知道  在离声带那么"近"的地方做手术
You know, it's very dangerous
是很危险的
operating so close to the vocal cords.
好了  我们会把你儿子的细胞送去化验室
Okay. Well, we'll send your kid's culture to the lab
之后会有人联系你们
and somebody will call you.
只是想看看你爸爸的反应  有点怪
Just wanted to see if your dad, you know- Bizarre.
你要穿上白大褂
I need you to wear your lab coat.
我要两天时间来和比你年轻得多的姑娘鬼混
I need two days of outrageous sex with someone obscenely younger than you,
也就你一半岁数的
like half your age.
穿上白大褂
Wear the coat.
老天  看来有人早上被狠狠地扇了一巴掌
Man, oh, man, someone got spanked real good this morning.
为了一个肯捐1亿用于癌症治疗的人
A guy gives $100 million to cure cancer.
我们只做一个很小的让步  穿上外套吧
A pretty small concession to wear a lab coat.
癌症治疗吗
Cure cancer?
现在医院不再忙着
Is the hospital getting out
治疗病人了吗
of the dull business of treating patients?
你知道他不是那样的
You know that's not what he's doing.
我很清楚他在干什么
I know exactly what he's doing.
他在利用我们做临床试验
He's using us to run clinical trials.
真可耻  用这么独特的方式救人
Oh, shame on him, saving lives like that.
这是不道德的
It's unethical.
你也要加入吗  我还以为咱们是一伙的
Oh, are you coming in too? I thought I had you convinced.
临床试验能拯救成千上万条生命
Clinical trials save thousands of lives.
他这是把病人当小白鼠用
He's using patients as guinea pigs.
医药公司一直都这么做
Pharmaceutical companies do that every day.
原来我们这里是医药公司啊
Are we a pharmaceutical company?
这样做会把为了痊愈不顾一切的病人推向
We're gonna wind up pressuring desperate patients...
对他们不利的一端  而我们坐收渔翁之利
into choices that are bad for them, good for us.
这样做将会降低护理效果
We're gonna compromise patient care.
我在跟哪个该死的说话呢
Who the hell am I talking to?
你怎么突然关心起道德缺失了
Suddenly ethical lapses are a major concern for you?
有意思的是你突然不在乎道德缺失了
What's interesting is it suddenly doesn't bother you.
就是说  如果你忽略道德问题  救了一个病人
So, if you ignore ethics to save one person
就令人钦佩
it's admirable,
但如果你这么做救了一千人  就是混蛋
but if you do it to save a thousand, you're a bastard.
他只是升级你的游戏规则而已
All he's done is taken your game and gone pro.
他不仅会干掉病人
He's not gonna kill a few patients.
还会毁掉这家医院的
He's gonna kill this hospital.
他花了3秒钟打量你
It took him three seconds to size you up.
惊喜啊  他竟然不喜欢你
And surprise, he doesn't like you.
穿上那该死的白大褂
Wear the damn coat.
你好  我是  福曼医生
Hello. I'm, uh, Dr. Foreman.
豪斯医生的同事
I work with Dr. House.
我们的初步化验显示你没什么问题
Our initial tests say you're fine.
我们认为你的血栓自行消失了
We think you had a clot, but it resolved on its own.
所以观察一夜确认一下
So, we're gonna keep you overnight to be safe,
明天就可以回家了
and you can go back home tomorrow...
或者回去继续工作
or back to work.
你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
快进来  需要给她静脉注射吗啡  赶快
Get in here! I need a line in her. I.V. Morphine, stat!
搞明白新董事长想干什么吗
You get any read on the new chairman of the board?
当然  他占了你的车位
Yeah, he took your parking space.
这可未必是坏消息
It's not necessarily bad news.
你看过重播的《盖里甘的岛》吗[电视剧名]
Do you ever watch Gilligan's Island reruns...
难道你真的认为
and really, really think
他们这次能逃出岛去吗
they're gonna get off the island this time?
我们还是做自我介绍好了  这又不伤人
We should introduce ourselves. It couldn't hurt.
给他烤个蛋糕吧
Make him a Bundt cake.
疼痛评分达到10的病人
A patient hit a 10 on the pain scale.
怎么解释这个问题
What would explain that?
腿部没有血栓  血管造影显示没有血栓
There was no clot in her leg. The angio was totally clean.
那肌肉活检的结果呢
What about the muscle biopsy?
排除了神经源性异常和肌原性异常
No neurogenic or myopathic abnormalities.
毛线虫病的结果也是阴性
She was also negative for trichinosis.
也不是弓形虫病和结节性多动脉炎
No toxoplasmosis or polyarteritis nodosa.
罗伯特  她的沉降率是多少
Robert, what was her sedimentation rate?
正常  艾莉森
Normal, Allison.
所以  没有炎症  也没有免疫反应
Therefore, no inflammation, no immunologic response.
介意告诉我具体数字吗
Do you mind sharing that number with me?
15  艾莉森
Fifteen, Allison.
-你在嘲笑我吗  -哪有  艾莉森
- Are you mocking me? - Duh, Allison.
我只是建议从多个角度进行考虑
I'm just suggesting we look outside the box.
如果她的沉降率升高了呢
What if her sed rate is elevated?
好吧  那让我们好好换角度考虑
Well, let's go further outside the box.
假设血管造影曾经显示有血栓
Let's say the angio revealed a clot.
后来我们治好了血栓
And then let's say we treated that clot,
而现在她感觉好多了
and now she's all better
还就我装作这样感谢我
and personally thanked me by performing-
我的埃丽莎姨妈住在费城
My Aunt Elyssa lives in Philadelphia.
到讲故事的时间了  我来讲讲我爸
Oh, it's story time. Let me get my "Baba."
她的正常体温是华氏96.2度
Her normal temperature is 96.2,
而不是像你我这样的98.6
not 98.6 like you and me.
如果她的体温到了华氏98.6度
If her temperature were 98.6,
就说明她发烧了
she'd have a fever.
我想知道你是否认为
I'm just wondering if you think
我们应该把相同的理论用于卡莉的沉降率上
we could apply the same logic to Carly's sed rate.
荒谬
It's absurd.
我喜欢这个主意
I love it.
如果对卡莉来说  15比正常数值要高
If 15 is high for Carly,
那她就有炎症
then she has inflammation.
也就有可能是癌症  我去找威尔森
Which could, in turn, mean cancer. I'll talk to Wilson.
下次  跳过埃丽莎姨妈那段
Next time, skip Aunt Elyssa.
恐怕你说的是原发性骨癌
You're probably talking about a primary bone cancer.
这种病很难发现
It could be tricky to detect.
我们需要给她做个骨扫描
We'll need a bone scan.
这就是我为什么来找你这个肿瘤学家
That's why I'm talking to an oncologist.
是啊  除了部门会议和预算报告
Sure. I've nothing better to do
我没什么事可做
besides departmental meetings and budget reports.
新官上任三把火啊  董事局的  知道吗
New chairman of the board, you know.
我可没听说
Oh, I hadn't heard.
-没错  临床试验论  -道德缺失
- Right. Clinical trials. - Completely unethical.
还有一个针对你的凶兆
And a very bad omen for you.
研究治愈非洲锥虫病的经费
There's not much money in curing
减少了
African sleeping sickness.
错了  我看过市面上所有的恐怖片
No. I have seen every scary movie ever made.
一对6岁的双胞胎站在满是血的电梯前
Six-year-old twins in front of an elevator of blood.
男童合唱  这些才是凶兆呢
Boys' choirs. Those are bad omens.
还有更俗的  亿万富翁想和女人上床
This is much more mundane. A billionaire wants to get laid.
亿万富翁买电影厂是为了女人
Billionaires buy movie studios to get laid.
买医院是为了声誉
They buy hospitals to get respect.
-那为什么他们要个好声誉  -找女人上床
- And the reason you want respect? - To get laid.
好的  那么  让我们像亿万富翁一样思考
Okay then. Just gotta think like a billionaire.
想想看  有个巨大又可怕的改变发生了
Let's see. There'll be big, scary changes
然后  富翁说 "卡梅隆医生
and then, "Oh, Dr. Cameron,
我们在我的G5私人飞机上
we should have dinner
一边吃晚餐一边讨论一下你的未来吧"
to discuss your future on my G5 private jet."
行了吧  你知道这里给你的条件有多好
Come on. You know how good you have it here.
是  是  我就是大佬  头儿  教父
Yes, I'm the big poobah, the big cheese, the go-to guy.
只在这里  你能仅对你感兴趣的病案挑三拣四
You do the cases you wanna do when you wanna do them.
-其他地方可没这特权  -放轻松
- You're not gonna have that anywhere else. - Relax.
我经历过这家医院三次易主了
I've been through three regime changes in this hospital.
每一次都会遇到一样的问题
Every time same story.
我就说一句  低调
Just keep your head down. That's all I'm saying.
-还有穿上白大褂  -那东西让我浑身发痒
- And put on your coat. - It itches.
那你会不会帮我做骨扫描啊
So, you gonna do this bone scan for me, or what?
我做
Yes.
辛普森医生  听说了吗  新老板
Dr. Simpson, did you hear? New management.
我正在考虑转到整形外科来
I'm thinking of switching to orthopedics.
你们现在按摩一次挣多少
How much do you guys get for a massage now?
在没干好的情况下
Without the happy ending.
豪斯医生  你想要干什么
Dr. House, what do you want?
你还记得一个叫范德米尔的家伙吗
Do you remember a guy named Van Der Meer?
他有点内向  你修好了他的 A.C.L
Not a big talker. You fixed his A.C.L.
没有  至少我的医疗事故责任险没告诉我
No, not according to my medical malpractice premiums.
手术中有低血压症状出现吗
Didn't get hypotensive during surgery?
中风  或者神经连接性降低
No strokes? Maybe some connectivity loss?
怎么  你现在掺和进来了吗
What, you're gonna get involved now?
我没有掺合进来
I'm not involved.
有个家伙带他儿子来门诊了
A guy brought his son into the clinic.
我可没碰他儿子
I didn't touch the son.
我一点责任都没有
I'm not taking any responsibility there.
他儿子很好  好得闭不上嘴
The son's fine. Can't shut him up.
父亲没有表现出脑皮层或者言语中枢病症吗
Dad show any symptoms of cortical disease? Wernicke's?
没有  什么都没有
No. Nothing.
因为什么也没发现  所以我们这样处理
That's why we settled because we couldn't find anything.
那家伙为此得到了一百万美元
The guy got over a million dollars.
别告诉我他还在抱怨
Don't tell me he's complaining.
他连嘘声都发不出
He's not saying boo.
您父亲想知道
Your father wants to know
您何时结束旅行回家
when you'll be back from your trip.
回复邮件告诉他  旅行时间超出了预计
E-mail back it's taking longer than I thought.
没有必要让他见到我这个样子
He doesn't need to see me like this.
和您兄弟说吗
What about your brother?
不要说
No.
你好  我是威尔森医生  我是来...
Hello. I'm Dr. Wilson. I was...
罗宾  麻烦你出去下
Um, Robin, I'm gonna need a minute.
谢谢
Thank you.
这家医院有两个威尔森医生
There are two Dr. Wilsons in this hospital,
一个是眼科医生  一个是肿瘤科医生
one in ophthalmology and one in cancer.
我的眼睛没问题
My eyes are fine,
所以我猜你是来告诉我  我得了癌症
so I'm guessing you're here to tell me that I have cancer.
你没有骨癌
There is no cancer in your bone.
你也没有笑容
You're not smiling.
有一种东西叫做牵涉性疼痛
There's something called referred pain.
可能是你身体的某部位有癌症
You could have cancer in one part of your body...
但在其他部位产生症状
that presents in another.
根据年龄和家族病史
Given your age and your family history,
我想你的结肠有些问题
I'm thinking your colon.
太好了
Great.
我妈妈去世时我在哥伦比亚  现在报应来了
I was at Columbia when my mom died. Now there's a blast.
那些清理出的呕吐物  都来找我了
Cleaning up her vomit, and then running to my econ final.
你看
Look.
要是我没几天  你就给我点儿药
If I'm a short-timer, give me drugs.
我要回去工作  死在我的岗位上
I'll go back to work. I'll die there.
我们可以通过一个快速检查得知
Whoa. There's a very quick test to see
你是否患有结肠癌  做个结肠镜检查
if you even have it- a colonoscopy.
我知道那个检查怎么做
I know how you do that test.
如果你患有结肠癌  我们有治疗方案
If you have colon cancer, we can treat it.
现在还是早期
It's early.
他们也是这样和我妈妈说的
That's what they told my mom.
然后6个月后她就去世了
She was dead six months later.
你很聪明  却做了个不明智的决定
You're a smart person about to make a very bad decision.
癌症治疗在这12年中有很大发展
You know, cancer treatment's come a long way in 12 years,
但如果你现在不做检查...
but if you don't do this now...
我不想让别人那样看我
I don't wanna be looked at.
还有别的方法
There is another way.
可以做个虚拟结肠镜检查
We could do a virtual colonoscopy.
大致上来讲  就是给你的结肠做一个CT
Basically, we do a C. T. Scan of your colon.
是非侵入性的
It's noninvasive.
但价格昂贵  我想这对你来讲不成问题
But it's very expensive. I'm assuming that's not a problem.
快同意吧
Say yes.
范德米尔先生
Mr. Van Der Meer.
什么
What?
放轻松  瑞奇会"没事"的
Relax. Ricky's gonna be just "Finkf."
他得了脓毒性咽喉炎
Strep throat.
这是张抗生素处方
Here's a prescription for an antibiotic.
过段时间他就会好了
He should be all better in a few days.
只不过  有点痛
Although, this might sting a little.
我盼望着与你早日相见
I wanna see you again real soon.
虚拟结肠镜检查显示没有任何问题
Virtual colonoscopy was clean.
她没有患结肠癌
No colon cancer.
怎么不做我们常规的老式结肠镜检查
What happened to our regular, old-fashioned colonoscopy?
做了那么多检查让她不舒服
She was uncomfortable doing any more tests.
我不得不说服她做这个
I had to convince her to do that one.
你经常遇到这样的状况吗
Do you get that often?
女性患者宁愿死也不愿意让你看到裸体
Women would rather die than get naked with you?
她很害怕
She's scared.
她不怕检查  是怕让她难堪的检查
But not of tests. Just embarrassing ones.
是啊
Yeah.
不是炎症
It's not an inflammatory process.
不是血块  因为奇斯的血管造影说不是
It's not a clot, because Chase's angio says so.
也不是癌症  因为她的骨头一点问题没有
And it's not cancer, because her tush is perfect.
还有谁能讲个埃丽莎姨妈的奇特事件
Anybody else got an Aunt Elyssa with weird stuff?
或许我们应该查查...
Maybe it's worth looking into-
我记得你说卡莉的血管造影是正常的
I thought you said Carly's angio was clean.
当时是正常的
It was clean.
你们看得出问题所在吗
You guys see the problem here?
没有任何反常迹象
There's no indication of any abnormalities.
没有病变  没有骨质增生  没有...
No lesions, no spurs, no mastis...
她的脚趾长得有问题  向后伸
Her toes are screwed up. They're backwards.
你们知道要做多少次手术
You guys know how much surgery
才能把它们扳回来吗
it's gonna take to swap 'em back?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
好吧  要不就是她确实有两只左脚
Well, either she literally has two left feet,
要不就是你的血管造影做错脚了
or you angioed the wrong leg.
不可能  不可能是...
That's impossible. It can't be...
或者是珍妮弄错了
Or maybe it was Jenny.
为什么是住院实习医生签的放射报告
How come some resident signed this radiology report?
你当时不在吗
Were you even in the room?
-我去重做她的血管造影  -你什么都别做
- I'll redo her angio- - You'll do nothing!
福曼  你去做血管造影
Foreman, you do the angiogram.
我居然做错了
I can't believe I did that.
为什么我们要重做血管造影
Why do we have to redo the angiogram?
-第一次造影结果里有阴影  -阴影
- There was a shadow on the first test result. - Shadow?
阴影意味着可能是血块  对吗
A shadow means there could be a blood clot, right?
我读过《康的当代疗法》
I read Conn's Current Therapy.
那的确是一部引人入胜的著作
A real page-turner.
不过不是那类阴影
No, it wasn't that kind of shadow.
-我的胸疼  -是注射的追踪剂的副作用
- My chest hurts. - It's from the tracer I injected.
可能还会恶心
You might also get a little nauseous
或闻到金属味  都是正常反应
or have a metallic taste. All normal.
我经常跑步  不应该有这样的感觉
I'm a runner. I shouldn't feel like this.
卡莉  我正在检查你的器官  而且...
Carly, I'm looking at your vitals right now and...
-喘不上气了  -卡莉
- I can't breathe. - Carly?
胸
My chest.
呼吸停止  呼叫求助
Respiratory arrest. Call code.
-怎么了  -她要憋死了
- What do you got? - She's drowning.
福曼做了胸腔穿刺
Foreman did a thoracentesis
来排出她肺部的积液
to drain the fluid from her lungs.
她现在情况稳定  他们把积液送去实验室了
She's stable. They sent the fluid to the lab.
几小时内就会有结果
It'll be back in a few hours.
你可以放心  奇斯的错误没有对她造成伤害
You'll be happy to know Chase's mistake didn't cost her.
血管造影结果显示没有血块
Angio revealed no clot.
我很庆幸
I'm thrilled.
好吧  你看  你就是太固执
Okay, see, now you're just being stubborn.
天冷了  这是个穿白大褂的完美理由吧
It's cold. It's a perfectly good excuse to wear your lab coat.
卡莉需要做心脏移植
Carly needs a heart transplant.
胸腔穿刺的积液化验结果说的
Thoracentesis revealed a transudate?
我还没有拿到结果
I haven't gotten it back yet.
她的放射性核素扫描射血分数
Her MUGA scan, what was the ejection fraction?
或许你可以用外科手术治疗
Maybe you could treat it surgically.
我没有做放射性核素扫描
I haven't done the MUGA.
那你怎么知道她需要做心脏移植
How do you know she needs a heart transplant?
我今天得到了灵性的指引
I got my aura read today.
它告诉我我身边的某人心碎了
It said someone close to me had a broken heart.
什么时候开始我和你要用密码说话
Since when do I need the secret pass code to talk to you?
我什么都不能告诉你  这是职业责任问题
I can't tell you anything. Professional responsibility.
就好像你在乎过这个似的
Like that matters to you.
不是我的职业责任  是你的
Not my professional responsibility, yours.
新政权下  你也得小心过日子
New regime. You gotta keep your head down too.
这真是好主意
Now that's good thinking,
因为我要在你说完话后
because I was gonna go right to Cuddy...
直接去找卡迪出卖你
and rat you out as soon as you were done talking.
我不是说你想那么做  而是说那是你的责任
I'm not saying you want to. I'm saying you'd be obligated to.
因为我在董事会有一席之地吗
Because of my position on the board?
还因为我在移植委员会有一席之地
Because of my position on the transplant committee?
你这么做总得有个理由  你得告诉我
Hey, you brought this up for a reason. You need to talk to me.
我不能
I can't.
你确定你做的事情是正确的
You sure you're doing the right thing?
我已经有了几个相当合理化的原因
I've come up with a few really great rationalizations.
抱歉打断你们  我们有个麻烦
Sorry to interrupt. We have a problem.
胸腔穿刺的结果出来了
Thoracentesis revealed a transudate.
我们多确认了一下
We did an echo.
她现在是严重充血性心力衰竭
She's in severe congestive heart failure.
她需要做心脏移植
She needs a heart transplant.
需要马上把她列入等待名单
We'll get her on the list immediately.
她已经在名单上了
She's already on the list.
进来
Come in.
谢谢
Thanks.
什么是医学诊断科
What is a department of Diagnostic Medicine?
那是豪斯医生的科室
That's Dr. House's department.
他们专攻其他医生解决不了的病案
They deal with cases that other doctors can't figure out.
那可是个财政上的黑洞
It's a financial black hole.
这个科室每年花费3百万美元
The department costs us three million a year...
每周才医治一名病人
to treat one patient a week.
他每周救一名病人
He saves one patient per week.
其他人怎么办
What about everyone else?
他的部门不是要寻找乳癌的治疗之道
His department's not going to find the cure for breast cancer.
或许不是  但是...
Uh, maybe not, but...
你在和豪斯上床吗
Are you sleeping with House?
什么  没有
What? No.
但你其实上过了  不是吗
But you did. Right?
在很久以前吗
A long time ago?
这是一个极不合适的问题
That's an incredibly inappropriate question.
如果你的判断被先前或现在的关系影响
If your judgment is compromised by a prior or current relationship,
那就是我的事了
that is my business.
我尊敬他  你知道这一点就够了
I respect him. That is all you need to know.
他还是没穿白大褂
He's still not wearing the coat.
这件事  我和他说...
Well, I told him...
我相信你说过了
I'm sure you did.
但他还是没有穿
And yet he's not wearing it.
我只是想知道这是他的回应
I'm just wondering if that's a reflection on him...
还是你的
or on you.
你是豪斯医生
You're Dr. House.
我在网上找到一张你出席某个会议的照片
I found a picture online of you at a conference.
你需要做心脏移植
You need a heart transplant.
-我经常跑步  在外工作  -你自虐
- I run. I work out... - You cut yourself.
可能是某种仪式化的行为
Probably highly ritualized.
你一边重复放莎拉·克劳克兰的歌
You play the same Sarah McLachlan song
一边自虐
over and over while you do it.
或许这种方法比抗抑郁药更有效
Probably works better than antidepressants.
我不明白是怎么...
I don't understand how that...
你是严重暴食症患者  你自己催吐
You're a high-powered bulimic. You make yourself throw up.
你必须找到一种最有效的方法催吐
You had to find the most efficient way to vomit
同时不能暴露出暴食症的蛛丝马迹
without revealing the telltale signs of bulimia,
对一位首席执行官来说  这是相当不合体的
which is all, ooh, very unseemly for a C.E.O.
所以  你找到了一种常见的
So, you found a common
对付意外中毒的解药来催吐
antidote to accidental poisoning to do the job-
吐根糖浆
Ipecac.
要是你的孩子刚吞下去一瓶阿司匹林
Which is great if your kid's just swallowed
这是个良方
a bottle of aspirin,
但是  要是用它成为习惯  就会相当糟糕
but really, really bad if it's a habit.
它会引起肌肉损伤
It causes muscle damage.
腿部的疼痛
It caused the pain in your leg.
还会毁掉你的心脏
And destroyed your heart.
你多久催吐一次
How often do you do it?
1周3次
Three times a week.
一小时内  移植委员会将会召开
In about an hour, there's gonna be
一个紧急会议
an emergency meeting of the transplant committee...
来讨论把你排在等待名单的位置
to discuss where you fall on the list
有没有心脏可以移植给你
should a new heart become available.
问题是  我必须告诉委员会你有暴食症
Problem is, I am required to tell the committee about your bulimia.
这是个严重的精神问题
It's a major psychiatric condition.
级别直逼自杀
Ranks right up there with suicidal.
这会让你负担一个糟糕的风险
Makes you a very bad risk.
所以  你是来这里告诉我
So, you're here to tell me
我只有几个小时可活了
I have just a few hours to live?
除非我对委员会说谎
Unless I lie to the committee.
但一旦他们发现  我就会丢掉我的行医执照
But if they find out, I lose my medical license.
这是个向我行贿的好机会
This would be a very good time to offer me a bribe.
你知道的  就是你的生命价值多少
You know, how much is your life worth?
你的工作价值多少
How much is my job worth?
为什么你要这么对我  你想要什么
Why are you here doing this to me? What do you want?
我想知道什么是对的
I wanna know what's right.
我值不值得救
Am I worth it?
你认为我很可怜
You think I'm pathetic.
有份不错的工作  拥有一切
Has a good job. Everything in the world.
只是不喜欢她自己的样子
But she just doesn't like the way that she looks.
别耍花样了
Oh, stop hiding!
我在问你  你是想活还是想死
I'm asking you if you wanna live or die?
你连这个都不知道吗
You can't even say that.
你想让我做什么  哭吗
What do you want me to do? Cry?
对
Yes.
我想让你告诉我
I want you to tell me that
你很在乎你的生命  因为我看不出来
your life is important to you, because I don't know.
因为现在讨论的是
Because that's what's on the table right now-
你的生命
your life.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
我不想
I don't.
这位32岁女性病人经我的下属确认
This 32-year-old female was admitted by my staff...
病因是右腿瘫痪疼痛
because of paralysis and pain in her right thigh.
病人情况迅速恶化
The patient rapidly deteriorated
而现在处于严重充血性心力衰竭中
and now has severe congestive heart failure.
升压剂和血管舒张剂
Pressors and vasodilators
也已经不能改善她的情况
have not improved her condition whatsoever.
肺功能测试显示用力呼气量超过3000ml
Pulmonary function tests show an F.E.C. of over three liters,
1秒用力呼气量达到预计的90%
with F.E.V. -1 of at least 90% of predicted...
维持F.E.D./F.E.C.比率
and preserved F.E.D./F.E.C. Ratio
和一氧化碳弥散量
and preserved D.L.C.O. as well.
放射性核素活动血管扫描结果提示射血分数为19％
Her MUGA had an ejection fraction of 19%
无局部心室壁运动异常
with no focal wall motion abnormalities.
冠状动脉造影提示
Heart catheterization revealed clean left,
左右冠脉及回旋支均正常
right and circumflex arteries.
随后活检表明
And a subsequent biopsy revealed
她有不可逆转的心肌病
irreversible cardiomyopathy.
这就是我们在此讨论的原因
Which is why we're here.
豪斯医生  我对你的时间和日期记录很疑惑
Uh, Dr. House, I'm confused by your time and date stamps.
记录显示在检查之前
It appears that you put Carly
你就把卡莉列入了移植名单
on the transplant list before you did these tests.
直觉
I had a hunch.
你从来都没有直觉  你只是知道事实
You don't have hunches. You know.
看  要是检查结果不同
Look, if the tests had come back differently,
显然我会把她从名单上去掉
obviously I would have taken her off the list.
但就长远来看...
But on the long shot...
就长远来看我当时的判断是正确的
On the long shot that I was right,
我不想浪费时间
I didn't want to waste time.
还有什么其他我们应当获知的排除标准吗
Is there any exclusion criteria we should know about?
CAT扫描显示没有肿瘤
CAT scan revealed no tumors,
威尔森医生没有发现癌症迹象
and Dr. Wilson found no trace of cancer.
还有其他排除标准吗
What about any other criteria?
没有动脉粥样硬化血管病
No atherosclerotic vascular disease.
有什么...
Are there any...
没有肺炎  没有菌血症
No pneumonia, no bacteremia.
没有乙肝  丙肝  或其他肝炎
No hep "B" Or "C" Or any other letters.
是否有药物滥用  任何用药史...
Substance abuse. Any history...
她不嗜酒  不吸毒
No alcohol. No drugs.
有什么精神病症吗
Any psychiatric conditions?
-忧郁症病史 -她有点郁闷
- History of depression? - She's a little blue.
但考虑到她正急需做心脏移植  所以...
But turns out she needs a heart transplant, so...
豪斯医生  如果你扰乱或者误导委员会
Dr. House, if you subvert or mislead this committee,
你将受到严惩
you will be subject to disciplinary action.
卡迪医生  你为什么认为我在撒谎呢
Dr. Cuddy, do you have reason to think that I would lie?
我只是要求你如实回答问题
I simply want you to answer the question.
接受人是否有任何排除标准
Is there anything on the recipient exclusion criteria...
会令你的病人失去获得心脏的资格
that would disqualify your patient from getting a heart?
没有
No.
多么美丽的器官捐赠天气
Beautiful organ donor weather.
你撒谎了  是不是
You lied, didn't you?
-我从不撒谎   -你犯了大错
- I never lie. - Big mistake.
那你该投票反对把她列入名单
Then you should have voted against putting her on the list.
-你是我的朋友  -老天  有点骨气吧
- You're my friend. - Oh, geez, have some backbone.
如果你认为我错了  那就做点什么吧
If you think I'm wrong, do something.
等等  你要因为我支持你而对我发火
Wait. You're getting mad at me for sticking up for you?
你重视我们的友谊超过了
You value our friendship more than
你的道德责任
your ethical responsibilities.
我们的友谊就是一种道德责任
Our friendship is an ethical responsibility.
怎么了
What is it?
我的病人要得到心脏了
My patient's getting a heart.
他不会解雇你的
He's not gonna fire you.
我会解雇你  再见
I'd fire you. Bye-bye.
我搞砸了  病人去世了
I screw up, the patient dies,
我将再也得不到其他工作
I'll never get another job.
那就从你的双腿间
So stick your head between
抬起头  再去格施塔德舔舔伤口
your legs and go lick your wounds in Gstaad.
其实  我喜欢这里
Well, I like it here.
你们不认为这事有点奇怪吗
You guys don't think it's weird
豪斯在我们做心脏检查前
House knew the patient needed a heart transplant...
就知道病人需要心脏移植
before we did any heart tests?
他是豪斯  他就知道
That's House. He knows things.
但通常他会当着我们的面说
But usually he's putting it in our face.
炫耀他有多聪明
Telling us how cleverly he figured it out.
这次却什么都没有  只说是他的直觉
This time nothing. Just had a hunch.
是挺奇怪
That is weird.
把那个出血分支灼烧消毒
Cauterize that one bleeder.
好的  准备好接收捐赠心脏
Okay, ready for the donor heart.
他们刚刚停止了卡莉的心脏机能
They just stopped Carly's heart,
还有你的哑病人...
and your dumb patient...
他们全都是笨蛋
They're all...
哦对  是那个不能说话的啊
Oh, the guy who can't talk.
范德米尔先生
Mr. Van Der Meer.
预约来见你
He's scheduled an appointment to see you.
很好
Oh, goody.
我想让你知道
I wanted you to know
奇斯担心你会解雇他
Chase is worried you're going to fire him.
因为失误丢掉生命就够糟了
It's bad enough that screw-ups cost lives.
现在我们有个沃格勒  失误会丢掉工作
Now we've got Vogler, screw-ups cost jobs.
我希望奇斯害怕
I want Chase scared.
我想让他竭尽所能去保住他的工作
I want him doing everything he can to protect his job.
豪斯医生  换位思考一下
Dr. House, if you were in his position,
难道你不会因为有人安慰你而表现的更好吗...
wouldn't you be more likely to perform well if you were reassured...
你能不能别看那些书了  为什么你要这么做
Oh, will you stop it with the book? Why are you doing this?
我没做什么
I'm not doing anything.
你在操纵每个人
You're manipulating everyone.
人们...  忽略我
People... dismiss me.
因为我是女性  因为我漂亮
Because I'm a woman. Because I'm pretty.
因为...  我不争强好斗
Because... I'm not aggressive.
我的意见不应该因为
My opinions shouldn't be rejected
人们不喜欢我就被驳回
just because people don't like me.
他们喜欢你
They like you.
每个人都喜欢你
Everyone likes you.
你呢
Do you?
我一定要知道
I have to know.
不喜欢
No.
好吧
Okay.
5小时23分钟  挺快的
Five hours, 23 minutes. That's fast.
-是好是坏  -要看情况
- Is that good or bad? - It depends.
要么是手术进展顺利  要么就突然停止了
Either surgery went really well, or it ended really abruptly.
理论上  她会比我们都长寿
Textbook. She'll outlive us all.
谢谢你
Thank you.
分拣护士  请接2741
Triage nurse, pick up line 2741.
好了  给我唱首歌吧
So, sing for me.
不  不  不  你看
Oh, no, no, no, no. Come on, look.
当你做手术的时候  你被插了管子
When you had your surgery, you were intubated.
外科医生把管子插入你的喉咙
The surgeon stuck a tube down your throat.
现在  虽然以前从没发生过
Now, it never happens and it's never caught,
但还是发生了
but it happened.
你的声带瘫痪了
Your vocal cords were paralyzed.
我用肉毒杆菌治疗了痉挛性失声
I treated the spastic dysphonia with Botox.
讽刺的是  这种物质
Ironically, a substance
能拉紧你脸上的每一个角落
that tightens every other corner of your face.
却会放松你的舌头
It actually loosens the tongue.
我已经把你治好了  你可以说话了
I have healed you. You can talk.
好吧
Oh, well.
Okay.
你不一定要说话  这是我们的小秘密
You don't have to say anything. It can be our little secret.
如果你能说话  眨两下眼
If you can talk, blink twice.
但你不那么做
But you're not going to,
因为你不想丧失和辛普森医生
because you think you won't be entitled
庭外和解那笔钱
to the money you won in the settlement with Simpson.
昨天的话  我会叫你
Yesterday, I would have said
把钱还回去
you had to give the money back.
今天  医院得到一大笔钱
Today, hospital's come into a lot of money.
我会保守秘密
Mum's the word.
我知道心脏病专家已经给了你一些指导
I know the cardiologist has given you some guidelines,
一个服药时间表  和一个严格的饮食要求
a schedule of medication and a strict diet.
正是某位饮食失调的人所需要的
Just what somebody with an eating disorder needs.
所以我想我得让你开始实施了
So I thought I'd get you started.
卡耐基餐馆的炸鸡
Fried chicken from the Carnegie Deli.
-你这是开玩笑  -没错
- You're kidding. - Yeah.
其实  我是从楼下买的
Actually, I got it downstairs.
为什么帮我
Why did you fight for me?
你冒了很大风险  而且并不怎么了解我
You risked so much, and you hardly know me.
你是我的病人
You're my patient.
别搞砸了
Don't screw it up.
爱死这段了
Love this part!
好吧  被他毁了
Okay. He ruined it.
只是想打断一下来个自我介绍
Just wanted to stop by and introduce myself.
我是爱德华·沃格勒  新任董事长
I'm Edward Vogler, new chairman of the board.
这样来讲  我猜我成了你的老板
In a way, I guess that makes me your boss.
对于白大褂的事情  我很抱歉
I am sorry about the lab coat thing.
我的干洗店把它毁了
My dry cleaners just destroyed it.
这是我第一次参加心脏移植委员会会议
That was my very first heart transplant committee meeting.
非常令人激动
Very exciting.
相信我  六旗主题公园更令人激动
Trust me, Six Flags- way more exciting.
你的病人有你这样热情的医生相当幸运
Your patient's very lucky to have such a passionate doctor.
为他坚信的事而奋斗
Stands up for what he believes in.
你说的真好
Sweet of you to say.
是啊  但恐怕你被骗了
Yeah. Afraid you've been duped though.
护士从病人的包里发现了这个
The nurse found this in the patient's purse.
天哪  要是我早知道就好了
Oh, my. If only I'd known.
做医生不容易吧  拥有所有的权力
Tough being a doctor, having all that power.
拥有扮演上帝的权力
The power to play God.
是啊  我不嫉妒移植委员会
Yes. I don't envy the transplant committee
的职责
their responsibility.
他们多半是被迫杀死那个可怜姑娘的
They basically would have been forced to kill that poor girl.
我可不确定我能那么做
I'm not sure I could have done that.
我可不认为这是游戏  豪斯医生
This is not a game to me, Dr. House.
没错  这更像是我们在跳舞
No. It's actually more like we're dancing right now.
那我们直截了当吧  你不喜欢我
So let's get to the point. You don't like me.
我也非常确信我不喜欢你
I'm pretty sure I'm not gonna like you.
不是针对你个人
It's nothing personal.
我谁都不喜欢
I don't like anybody.
但这些都无所谓  不是吗
But none of that really matters, does it?
因为你得到了钱  而我得到聘用
Because you've got money, and I've got tenure.
你需要全体董事会同意才能开除我
You need full board approval to get rid of me.
我有卡迪的支持
I've got Cuddy.
-是啊  -还有威尔森
- Right. - And Wilson.
那么  在我们还得拴在一起的日子里
So, as long as we're stuck with each other,
我们还是忽视对方存在比较好
we might as well ignore each other.
我原来没想要这么戏剧化的效果
That wasn't nearly as dramatic as I was hoping.
我想了想聘用的事情  觉得你是对的
I looked into that tenure thing, and you're right.
其实对我来说
It's actually easier for me
开除个像卡迪或者威尔森那样的成员
to get rid of a board member like Cuddy or Wilson...
比开除个医生要简单的多
than to get rid of a doctor.
很有趣  是不是
That's interesting, isn't it?